if you've been shell scripting for any
amount of time you probably used the
type command
typ and you might be doing it wrong in
fact it was some years back that I
discovered this difference and here's
the answer from Chad GPT about why you
might want to do
command-v uh the command-v is better
than type in certain scenarios such as
non-interactive shell scripts because it
is specified by posix and has a more
predictable Behavior it only outputs the
file name of the script or command to be
executed while type must return Alias as
functions blah blah blah which makes it
a more complex tool and less safe in
scripts intended for wi spread a across
different systems moreover command-b is
available on a larger variety of systems
and shells than the type command so it's
more portable so if you aim for maximum
portability and simplicity use
command-v
instead uh and just to give you a sense
of this um I did several comparisons
here so first of all if you do type
Schmo Schmo is an alias and um let's
actually Echo the last
um the the the oopsie the last
return um and let's do so Schmo is an
alias if I
do uh command-
VM it does say it's an alias which I
find fascinating because this answer
from chat
GPT might be
wrong
because that showed me the
Alias k-b Schmo was not able to do the
right
thing
um
so I don't know I don't know that does
make me interested um I do want to like
get onto a BSD system and see um let's
try it with a let's try it with a here's
clone clone is a function and it it
resolves it like that if I do type
you'll get the full function there's a
whole video on the Clone function and
let's do something you know predictable
like
LS type LS oh well let's not use LS
let's use date all right so date uh
command-v date at user bin date
so so that is pretty
predictable uh give that give that a
shot give that a look uh I would love to
hear in the comments if you've used the
if you've used this before I've started
putting command-b and everything um
because I wanted to work in in posic
Shell as well as bash um I'm concerned
that the command command in bash is
actually not the same as in a and other
things but take a look um but yeah it's
purported to be more AC crossplatform
and if for no other reason that's
probably better than type I do use type
from the command line interactively all
the time it's easier to type and
everything but whenever I'm in a shell
script and I want to make sure that I'm
checking for the existing sub command uh
I use command for that